<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SalahDin Ahmed</title><link>https://salastro.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on SalahDin Ahmed</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://salastro.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Leaving Social Media for Good</title><link>https://salastro.github.io/posts/productivity/leaving-social-media/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salastro.github.io/posts/productivity/leaving-social-media/</guid><description>In my humble opinion, the way modern social media is being used can&amp;rsquo;t be more toxic. We don&amp;rsquo;t really engage, have fun, or learn. You waste hours of your life doing nothing but scroll through an endless stream of meaningless content. Human lives should be wasted on nothing like this. I won&amp;rsquo;t be talking about why to leave, you are here because you already want to leave.
Why it&amp;rsquo;s so hard to leave It is no secret that social media companies improve their products every single day.</description></item><item><title>The Programming of Wizards</title><link>https://salastro.github.io/posts/programming/apl/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salastro.github.io/posts/programming/apl/</guid><description>APL (A Programming Language) is an exceptionally unique language. It mainly follows an array paradigm, unlike the usual functional and object-oriented approaches; it depends heavily on weird mathematical glyphs; and it is surprisingly elegant.
History of Old Wizardy APL is a quite old language. It started as a book (under the same name) written by Kenneth Eugene Iverson in 1962. The focus of the book was mathematical notation. Ken was dissatisfied with the inconsistency of mathematical notation and the lack of a sufficient tool to describe computer algorithms especially when it comes to matrices.</description></item><item><title>A Linux dead simple guide!</title><link>https://salastro.github.io/posts/linux/which-distor/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 01:44:13 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://salastro.github.io/posts/linux/which-distor/</guid><description>Introduction What is a Linux distribution Linux distributions usually refers to a family of operating systems that uses the Linux kernel and are similar in some design aspects. For the most part, Linux distributions follows the Unix philosophy and are Unix-like operating systems.
Distro is just a shorthand for distribution!
Does it even matter So little, most things that can be done on Linux can be done on all distros. Distros are more of an entry point, how you would like your system to look like when you start using it.</description></item></channel></rss>