<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on SalahDin Rezk</title><link>https://salastro.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on SalahDin Rezk</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://salastro.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Profound Significance of Prayer</title><link>https://salastro.github.io/posts/philosophy/prayer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salastro.github.io/posts/philosophy/prayer/</guid><description>Introduction Within the chaotic and unpredictable nature of human existence, the act of prayer emerges as a profound source of order and stability. It provides individuals with a framework to orient themselves, find meaning in their actions, and make sense of the bewildering world around them. Through regular engagement in prayer, individuals establish a structured routine that permeates their lives, offering a sanctuary of stability and purpose. Thus it becomes necessary to delve into the depths of prayer, exploring its physical, spiritual, and philosophical dimensions, unveiling the profound connection between the remembrance of death and this sacred act.</description></item><item><title>Thy Destiny</title><link>https://salastro.github.io/posts/philosophy/thy-destiny/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salastro.github.io/posts/philosophy/thy-destiny/</guid><description>Envision thyself as the person thou desirest to become, painting a vivid and intricate portrait of thy future self within the realm of thy mind&amp;rsquo;s eye. Contemplate not only the accomplishments and accolades thou seeketh, but also the qualities and virtues that shall define thee as an individual. Reflect upon the noble goals thou shalt pursue, the profound impact thou shalt have upon the world, and the legacy thou aspirest to leave behind.</description></item><item><title>Forever Alone</title><link>https://salastro.github.io/posts/philosophy/alone/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salastro.github.io/posts/philosophy/alone/</guid><description>The thought that hunts those who think of us the most is being of a something greater than ours. It is the search for the meaning that we crave for to fulfil our existence in life. We aim for something other than the manifestation that we acquire because of our realization of its incompleteness. Even the most narcissistic of us seek in similar vain. I may even argue that the only difference between who were deemed sane and those who are not is a corruption in the essence of meaning.</description></item><item><title>Embrace Death</title><link>https://salastro.github.io/posts/philosophy/death/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salastro.github.io/posts/philosophy/death/</guid><description>Death, the most detested of the experience (i.e. life) from the majority of whom endure. People hate, avoid, and even fight it, but no matter the struggle with that edifice, it will devour you and everyone close to your heart. You will have—even if you hate to—accept it.
My philosophy, on the other hand, is to embrace it; make it an irreplaceable ingredient in your daily life. Start every morning with talking to death, plan your day as if it is with you, and sleep every night while perceiving it.</description></item><item><title>Is Area a Vector or Scalar?</title><link>https://salastro.github.io/posts/physics/area/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salastro.github.io/posts/physics/area/</guid><description>In grade 10 we had a discussion with our mechanics and mathematics teacher about how should area be described. He insisted that area is a scalar, while some of us were totally convinced that it should be a vector. I, personally, was on the scalar side since vectors always have a direction, and area can not have such a characteristic. The only vector related to area is the normal to its surface, which is looked to me as a completely separate thing from area itself.</description></item><item><title>Leaving Social Media for Good</title><link>https://salastro.github.io/posts/productivity/leaving-social-media/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salastro.github.io/posts/productivity/leaving-social-media/</guid><description>In my humble opinion, the way modern social media is being used can&amp;rsquo;t be more toxic. We don&amp;rsquo;t really engage, have fun, or learn. You waste hours of your life doing nothing but scroll through an endless stream of meaningless content. Human lives should be wasted on nothing like this. I won&amp;rsquo;t be talking about why to leave, you are here because you already want to leave.
Why it&amp;rsquo;s so hard to leave It is no secret that social media companies improve their products every single day.</description></item><item><title>The Programming of Wizards</title><link>https://salastro.github.io/posts/programming/apl/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salastro.github.io/posts/programming/apl/</guid><description>APL (A Programming Language) is an exceptionally unique language. It mainly follows an array paradigm, unlike the usual functional and object-oriented approaches; it depends heavily on weird mathematical glyphs; and it is surprisingly elegant.
History of Old Wizardy APL is a quite old language. It started as a book (under the same name) written by Kenneth Eugene Iverson in 1962. The focus of the book was mathematical notation. Ken was dissatisfied with the inconsistency of mathematical notation and the lack of a sufficient tool to describe computer algorithms especially when it comes to matrices.</description></item><item><title>VIM BRAIN</title><link>https://salastro.github.io/posts/programming/vimbrain/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salastro.github.io/posts/programming/vimbrain/</guid><description>An obscure little project that I finished recently was to create an esoteric programming language. My goal was to achieve the smallest possible set of vim-like instructions while being Turing-complete.
However, I am not the first one to try to do this. The first language to be Turing-complete with only 6 instructions was P′′ (P double prime) in 1964. Despite that, a variation from it created in 1993 got more popular.</description></item><item><title>A Linux dead simple guide!</title><link>https://salastro.github.io/posts/linux/which-distor/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 01:44:13 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://salastro.github.io/posts/linux/which-distor/</guid><description>Introduction What is a Linux distribution Linux distributions usually refers to a family of operating systems that uses the Linux kernel and are similar in some design aspects. For the most part, Linux distributions follows the Unix philosophy and are Unix-like operating systems.
Distro is just a shorthand for distribution!
Does it even matter So little, most things that can be done on Linux can be done on all distros. Distros are more of an entry point, how you would like your system to look like when you start using it.</description></item></channel></rss>