<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Philosophy on SalahDin Rezk</title><link>https://salastro.github.io/posts/philosophy/</link><description>Recent content in Philosophy on SalahDin Rezk</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://salastro.github.io/posts/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sorrows of the Inadequate Soul</title><link>https://salastro.github.io/posts/philosophy/sorrows-of-the-inadequate-soul/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salastro.github.io/posts/philosophy/sorrows-of-the-inadequate-soul/</guid><description>I find myself engulfed in a profound disorientation, borne from the acute realization of my own inadequacy. Every fiber of my being resonates with a palpable sense of limitation, leaving me bereft of any semblance of fulfillment. I harbor naught but a fervent desire for the release of death upon my humble soul, for it struggles to grasp the boundless potential within, a potential thwarted not by external circumstances, but rather by my own inability to rise to the standards I have set.</description></item><item><title>The Profound Significance of Prayer</title><link>https://salastro.github.io/posts/philosophy/prayer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salastro.github.io/posts/philosophy/prayer/</guid><description>Framework of Orientation, Transience of Existence, Meaning Amidst Chaos</description></item><item><title>Thy Destiny</title><link>https://salastro.github.io/posts/philosophy/thy-destiny/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salastro.github.io/posts/philosophy/thy-destiny/</guid><description>Envision thyself as the person thou desirest to become, painting a vivid and intricate portrait of thy future self within the realm of thy mind&amp;rsquo;s eye. Contemplate not only the accomplishments and accolades thou seeketh, but also the qualities and virtues that shall define thee as an individual. Reflect upon the noble goals thou shalt pursue, the profound impact thou shalt have upon the world, and the legacy thou aspirest to leave behind.</description></item><item><title>Forever Alone</title><link>https://salastro.github.io/posts/philosophy/alone/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salastro.github.io/posts/philosophy/alone/</guid><description>The thought that hunts those who think of us the most is being of a something greater than ours. It is the search for the meaning that we crave for to fulfil our existence in life. We aim for something other than the manifestation that we acquire because of our realization of its incompleteness. Even the most narcissistic of us seek in similar vain. I may even argue that the only difference between who were deemed sane and those who are not is a corruption in the essence of meaning.</description></item><item><title>Embrace Death</title><link>https://salastro.github.io/posts/philosophy/death/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salastro.github.io/posts/philosophy/death/</guid><description>Death, the most detested of the experience (i.e. life) from the majority of whom endure. People hate, avoid, and even fight it, but no matter the struggle with that edifice, it will devour you and everyone close to your heart. You will have—even if you hate to—accept it.
My philosophy, on the other hand, is to embrace it; make it an irreplaceable ingredient in your daily life. Start every morning with talking to death, plan your day as if it is with you, and sleep every night while perceiving it.</description></item></channel></rss>